[news playing on radio]The serial blasts
that took place in Bombay on 12th March...
LONPUR
I don't want to hear the news.
Switch to the match.
[match commentary on radio]
Vinod Kambli has lost his wicket...
Oh man, Vinod Kambli
lost his wicket too.
Don't worry.
India will win today's match.
Really?
Yes, by losing all
their wickets quickly.
Don't switch to the news,
I will be right back.
-Hurry up.
-Yeah I will.
Hey Shopan!
12 HOURS EARLIER
What is wrong Bablu?
Nobody needs to see this.
Ew... Dirty...
And who asked you to help?
Now who will clean up this vomit?
I was just trying to save his...
save his life.
I am only joking.
Sorry.
Hello, I am Jayavrat Saini.
I spoke to you on the phone.
You are Mrs. Henriques?
Mrs. H. Everybody calls me Mrs. H.
Including my dead husband.
-I heard there was a room to rent?
-Yes, yes, yes.
-Come I will show you to your room.
-Oh okay yeah.
Pintu, get the bags.
So what brings you here?
I came to Lonpur
to search for something in
Mangal Ashram.
Oh. What?
Myself.
That's nice.
I live downstairs and
you will live upstairs.
You will have your own room
but you will have to share everything
else with the other tenant.
And this is your home.
Oh my god, what a mess!
-Please... sit. Sit.
-No thanks.
This is your room.
Pintu, give me the key.
-I don't have the key.
-Then who has it?
-Shekhar has it.
-Shekhar has it?
The key to both the rooms?
Oh that blessed boy.
God knows where he goes
or what he does.
Pintu, go and find
Shekhar immediately.
Hurry up.
Mrs. H if this is going
to take some time
then can I go take a
look around Lonpur?
Oh yeah, yeah. Great idea.
Please, please go.
Thank you.
-Let's go.
-Hurry!
Where is this Shekhar fellow?
Do we have to walk the
entirety of Lonpur on foot?
Not at all.
Let's take a rickshaw.
Hey rickshaw!
Does this Shekhar roam around
all day or does he also have a job?
He does. He runs a school
for children,
reads a lot of books,
plays music on his Rubab.
And he even does black magic.
What does that mean?
Mental black magic. You would be
blown away if you saw it yourself.
Hey man, where are you going?
Hey, where are you
taking my goat? Thief!
-You are the thief.
-You are stealing from me and calling me a thief?
This is Ganguly's goat.
Should I call Laha?
He will throw you in jail.
Hey thief! Stop him!
Hey Pintu!
Hold this.
You?
Dressed like this?
Why are you driving a rickshaw?
Ganguly's goat was stolen so
I brought his rickshaw with me.
How is a goat
related to a rickshaw?
This. It's a unique bell.
When Ganguly comes
home every evening
he rings the bell and
the goat runs to him.
-The bell is for?
-His food.
Pavlov's theory?
Classic case of conditioning.
I saw this herd of goats
and rang the bell.
All the goats kept
staring straight ahead.
But one of them...
did that.
Shekhar, this is...
The new tenant.
My new roommate.
If you ever have a bone stuck
in your throat you can visit him.
He will press your stomach
and get it out
because he knows the
Heimlich technique.
He was a doctor in the army.
Yes, I was. But... how do you know?
Black magic.
You came here with Pintu which means
you have been to the cafe already.
Today is the first,
the day everyone gets their salary.
Have Montu and Bablu started partying
since the morning like always?
Were they stuffing their mouths
with chicken like they always do?
Yes.
So of course he choked.
He administered the
Heimlich maneuver
and Bablu threw up,
he dodged it but not entirely.
Some of the vomit got
on his sleeve
and a tiny bit got on his shirt.
Ganguly!
Go on, take your goat.
And make sure to
fill air in your tyres.
Cycling was so tough with those.
But how did you figure
out that I was in the army?
The shrapnel wound on your neck.
Your soldier's gait.
You might be a little fat because
you left the army a long time ago
but you still keep your shoes immaculately
clean like a young cadet would.
This is excellent.
No Doctor...
It's Elementary.
Don't touch my things Henry.
Don't mess my home!
I am your home. Shekhar Home.
And you're late on rent.
Rent will be...
What is your name?
-Uh... Jayavrat.
-Jayavrat.
He will be staying here.
You can take his deposit.
Really?
And how do you know that?
You came all the way to Lonpur,
administered the Heimlich,
dodged the vomit,
sat in a cycle-rickshaw,
saw the goat,
and then you came back
here and made some space
to comfortably
take off your shoes.
Of course he is staying.
Actually Mrs. H, if you don't mind
can I try living here for a week?
Just until I visit the Ashram.
-Yeah, yeah, no problem Jayavrat.
-Thank you.
Meditation?
-Inner peace?
-Yes.
Now don't you dare mess
with his inner peace Shekhar!
No, no, no,
no smiling Mr. Shekhar Home.
I am serious.
I am...
I am warning you.
If he leaves too then you will
have to pay double rent.
Think about it!
Don't worry, he is harmless.
I am sure.
And just make yourself--
At home.
Thank you.
Well, it looks like
you have scared away
a lot of Mrs. H's tenants.
She was talking about Michael.
Poor Michael.
The first tenant.
By the way,
I have never heard the last name
Home anywhere in India before.
What? Amol Home?
Famous educationist?
Ajay Home. Ornithologist? No?
Sumendra Home? Bhaskar Home?
Yashodhara Home?
Charudatta Home?
No?
Never heard of them.
It's okay.
At least you know one Home.
Shekhar Home.
After all, home is
where the heart is.
Oh. Who could it be so early
in the morning?
Inspector Laha.
Inspector?
He bought new shoes.
The left one is biting him so he is
putting more pressure on the right.
He is walking fast because he is
excited. He has some big news.
Good morning Laha!
You didn't bring sweets?
It's your first murder case and
you still came here empty-handed?
How did you know that...
Take a seat.
-No I am fine--
-It's not good for your bowels. Sit.
He has two spoonfuls of digestives
before going to sleep at night.
And in the morning
he drinks warm water
and spends one full
hour in the bathroom.
But today he is here
early in the morning.
Which means something big
just happened.
In a boring town like Lonpur
where the cops spend their time
playing cards or carrom,
what could be bigger than a murder?
You are joking around?
Look, this... this is
the first murder case
I have ever worked on in my life.
Murder.
And you are joking about it?
This case... Shekhar?
Shekhar this case
is extremely baffling.
So can we go solve it?
Let's go?
I need you Shekhar.
Let's go Jayavrat.
What? Me?
Why me? I am going to the Ashram.
Who is this?
-Introduce.
-Jayavrat Saini.
I am the new tenant here.
He is a doctor.
He will be helpful
at the crime scene.
Let's go.
So you are a detective?
Some call me a Truth Seeker, some
call me a private investigator
and others call me a high-functioning
sociopath. Which do you prefer?
Two security guards found
this body here last night.
But how did this body reach all
the way over here in this forest?
-On foot.
-Yes...
He died by poisoning.
Poisoning?
By the way,
it was impossible for someone to
bring a body to
the jungle last night.
Because the CM was passing
through the city last night.
Only emergency vehicles
were allowed to move around.
And... So... I mean,
how could this have happened?
Laha you said this
was an adult crime.
-Yes.
-Then why does he have a 'U' certificate?
U...
Oh my God.
Hey, come here.
Yes sir?
Check the missing persons list
for people whose names start
with 'U'. Like Uttam, Uttaran...
Ulook(Idiot). Ujbook(Moron).
Why are you still here? Go.
There is no need to abuse in
front of everyone.
You could have said
it when we were alone.
This 'U' was made by the killer,
Udgandu(Dunce).
Oh wow. So, then...
that 'U' is a signature?
Does that mean the
killer's name starts with 'U'?
What is your opinion doctor?
Come in.
Yes, poisoning.
Chemical?
-Possible.
-Which one?
Cyanide?
Sodium?
-Potassium.
-Doctor.
Look around you.
Where would he find it?
Maybe he used a wild plant.
-Barbiturates--
-Not bad!
-Give me your handkerchief.
-Sir?
There is another suspect.
-Really?
-He came into town and there was a murder.
He was roaming around the
market yesterday.
He knows the name of the poison
his name starts with J but he used
a 'U' to create a double-bluff.
Wow. Very good.
He used medical
students to carve a 'U'.
Not to mention, the Doctor here
knows how to use a scalpel.
Yes, however...
this is the work of an amateur.
I am a good doctor.
You're joking?
Well, at least we know that this
is probably a medical student.
But who is he to the victim?
Teacher? He could have failed in--
He works in a bank.
I see...
He was a cashier.
How... How do you know?
The wallet is empty.
Look at his fingers.
The skin on his forefinger
and thumb have swollen up
because of counting
money every day.
And do you see the blue ink
on the side of his hand?
It must have come from
stamping documents.
By the way,
it is possible that is the horseshoe
symbol instead of the letter 'U'.
I know.
If you already know everything
then why did you bring me along?
You could have let
me go to the Ashram.
What a ruthless man,
there is a man lying dead there
and you want to visit an Ashram?
By the way, they serve Veg food
so you can't save anyone
from choking on a bone.
Is this how you behave with
everyone or am I special?
You need the thrill doctor,
not an Ashram.
Mr. Shekhar Home, there is
a limit to arrogance.
Yes, but there is
no limit to genius.
Today's test is observation. Okay?
Okay.
Here you go.
One! Two! Three!
Now start.
What is the news Laha?
Yes, I... have some big news.
You see...
What you said?
You were right. He was a cashier.
Manoj Kumar Jha.
He was cheating on his wife
and then he got caught.
He was very depressed.
He was under a lot of stress.
Maybe that is why he...
Suicide.
You see,
this is how the people who
have affairs always end up.
Is that how everyone who
has an affair ends up?
Yes...
No, I am... Just... Happy family.
And where did he
get the poison Laha?
And what does the 'U' stand for?
The 'U' is probably
the lady's name.
These lovers can
do anything for love.
Forget about all that.
Listen to what I am doing.
I am getting a list of
all the young ladies whose names start
with 'U' from the Lonpur Municipality.
Like Urmila, Urvashi, Upasana etc.
In just two days we will know exactly
who he was having an affair with.
And this list... Urvashi, Urmila etc.
Is that for your personal use?
-What?
-Manoj is already dead.
So what will you do with the list?
Try to see if you can score?
No, no, no...
This is a murder Laha!
It is a suicide Shekhar.
Don't make an open-and-shut case
so complicated.
You see, Laha has
already solved this case.
Five! Four!
-Fantastic.
-Sir?
Three!
Two! One!
Stop, stop, stop.
Show me. Show me.
Oh! When did this happen?
Henry forced me to take it.
I think she is in love with you.
That was inevitable.
By the way, if we are planning
on living together we should
co-ordinate a bit better.
Because I can't eat four kgs
of spinach in one week.
Okay, we will give it
away to people.
This is a list of herbs.
Figure out which herb
was used in the poison.
Mr. Home,
I came here to live as a paying
guest not to be your assistant.
They are going to find
another dead body, hurry up.
What?
We don't have the time to be
drinking tea.
-Why?
-Shekhar...
...That...
Shall we go Jayavrat?
[news playing on radio] Someone has been murdered
in Lonpur after almost 15 years.
A dead body was found yesterday
in the western section
of the Lonpur forest.
The public is scared.
Less than 24 hours
after this incident
we have received news of another
dead body being found near the river.
The authorities have decided
to keep schools and
colleges closed for two days.
Can we hear that
'U' theory again Laha?
I wasn't totally wrong.
We got a missing report for
'U' for Urvashi at the station yesterday.
Do you mean the report
filed by Das Gupta?
Felis catus kingdom animalia.
Order Carnivora family Felidae.
What does that mean?
It means that
Urvashi is a cat Laha.
Urvashi is a cat?
I have...
There was a call from
the Calcutta forensic team.
The poison has been traced.
Kulkhushan.
-Colchicine.
No, no, please go ahead.
It is a local herb.
Causes death in seconds.
Thank you Mr. Assistant.
-Laha?
-Yes?
All the poisoning cases that took
place near this area in the last year.
-Get me information on them.
-Okay.
So, two murders with
the same pattern?
Only curtains have patterns.
This is known as Modus Operandi.
And what do you call a
pompous trickster in latin?
Good luck charm.
What do you mean?
I mean that some people think
a horseshoe is a good luck charm.
I should have gone
to the Ashram after all.
The soldier is free to do
what he wants.
-Are you okay?
-Yes, I am.
My stomach hurts a bit...
Laha!
Does it hurt a lot?
I am sure he must have
eaten a puchka on the streets.
Why do you even go there Shekhar?
This black salt smells so bad.
-Oh Henry...
-Wait.
I will get you juice from
Kalmegh leaves.
Thank you Mrs. H.
How could I eat such bland food...
Hey Pintu!
Hurry up and get me...
-...a box of red chilli powder.
-What?
But if Henry finds out you will
be in big trouble. Now go.
Shekhar are you insane?
Your stomach hurts and
you want red chilli powder?
How will I eat such
bland food Laha?
Laha? What do you mean Laha?
-Oh, hello inspector.
-Yes, hello.
What is the news?
The news is that...
there is a small hospital in Bardhaman
district - Rangamati nursing home.
We found three cases of the
Kulkhushan poison there.
-Three? Really?
-Here you go.
Hey Shekhar! Please don't do that.
Please.
Please go to Bardhaman Nursing home
or whatever it is called with him.
Why should I go? He is a cop.
Why don't you send him?
That is the problem.
Last time he found a cat
maybe he will find
a giraffe this time.
Shekhar this is too much.
You are crossing your limit.
Don't do that.
Look, I am a senior police officer.
I have some prestige after all...
Calm down Laha sir.
He is just kidding.
But why?
-Because he is your friend.
-Does that mean he can insult me?
Okay fine. I will come with you.
Let's go.
Shekhar I will go
check it out, but you
will not eat red chillies.
You will only eat medicines.
What would I have
done without you?
You would have
to pay double rent.
Laha! Listen.
Giraffe please.
You will die shitting.
No, he will die of dysentery,
cholera and loose motions.
Laha! Someone who was spying
on us just ran away!
I will go that way.
Did you murder people?
Did you murder them?
Hey Laha, Laha.
Just wait a minute. Just wait.
There were three murders
caused by poisoning.
You know who did it right?
Look at me.
Tell me.
He used to work here when
those three people died.
He was crazy sir.
There was something
wrong with him.
He doesn't work here any more sir.
I heard that he now drives
a private ambulance.
What is his name?
Debu.
Such is life Kali da.
If someone saw you they would never
believe that you are not sick.
That was some good acting.
I am sure you lied to your mother
a lot when you were young.
"I don't want to go to
school mummy."
"Why?"
"My stomach hurts.
I am going to throw up!"
Do you recognise this?
Pushpavalli.
My boy...
eating this raises your heartbeat.
And you only ate as
much as you needed to.
How did you find out about me?
You told me.
The CM was passing
through the city last night.
Only emergency vehicles
were allowed to move around.
Emergency means...
Police, Fire Brigade...
Ambulance.
So why not a police van?
A cop doesn't use a scalpel.
By the way, I also found
tyre tracks of your car.
Your logic makes no sense.
Those could be anyone's tyre marks.
Ramp. Ramp.
The ramp used to drop a
patient off and pick them up
will only be found in an ambulance.
When we found the first
dead body in the national park
the ground was covered in leaves.
So I couldn't find any marks there.
Now that is impressive my friend.
Shekhar Home.
Debu.
That is a very small name.
I have a bigger name.
Debnath Chaudhary.
I like the other one better.
It's much better when it was smaller.
Debu, Debu, Debu.
Whose good luck charm
is a horseshoe.
Who takes a scalpel and carves
a horseshoe into his
victim's body as a signature.
Debu, today is a waste for you.
Why?
I don't have any money.
Oh come on now...
What fun is killing for money?
I like playing games.
You could say that I used to
bet money on every single match.
But eventually I got bored.
You know how it goes.
40 rupees on 4 runs.
60 rupees on a sixer.
Then I started playing the lottery.
Put some money in. If you're
lucky you will be rich.
Otherwise you get
kicked to the curb.
So one could say
that you were a patient
to the disease called luck.
And then you started playing
with the luck of patients.
Once a patient enters the hospital
the wheel of fate starts spinning.
That is what doctors play with.
So we did the same.
But when the wheel of fate is jammed
your wagon can't keep rolling.
I started losing.
And that is why you started killing
patients so that you could win.
Is winning wrong?
I am sure it must be quite
difficult to convince people.
There was no need to convince them.
People are always scared.
All I did was offer them
two capsules.
One would put them to sleep.
One would kill them.
Pick whichever one you want.
The rest is up to fate.
But there are a few people...
who enjoy ruining the game.
They refuse to pick a capsule.
Isn't that unfair?
That forces me to
give them the injection.
So whoever chooses
the sleeping pill
forgets everything the next day?
Yes but they also get
the money they won.
I don't steal from
the people who lose,
I take the exact
winning amount of the bet.
You are honest
and kind, Debu.
My mother used to say
the same thing.
I have always been very kind.
Let's suppose I didn't
come here tonight
Then what would you have done?
All of the victims were
found on this route.
This is your route.
Of course you would come here.
I don't have a good
luck charm like you do.
What will you do now?
How about heading
to the police station?
Oh my goodness...
Why don't we head to the morgue?
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe,
Catch a tiger by the toe.
If he hollers, let him go,
Eeny, meeny, miny...
Debu is a good small name...
Short name...
We are tracking every single
ambulance in the area.
And put an alert out
for the name Debu.
Anything else? Doctor?
Laha!
Shekhar? You?
One day I'll have a heart
attack because of you.
That is why I brought an ambulance.
But why are you roaming
around in an ambulance?
Because I couldn't find a cab.
-What?
-This...
Kulkhushan. Proof.
Kul...
The killer is in the back.
-What?
Hey Debu!
So you gave all of
the credit to Laha?
He wants a promotion and I
want more cases.
It's a win-win situation.
Win-win?
What if you ate the wrong
capsule on that night?
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe,
Catch a tiger by the toe.
What does that mean?
Density.
A Colchicine capsule is heavy
so the capsule that was
being moved by the wind
was the one that I chose.
And then you didn't
even eat that capsule.
I want to get into that
head of yours Mr. Home.
Henry.
-Henry?
-Yes, because one week is up.
-Oh my God!
-Good morning Mrs. H.
What have you done?
My house looks so clean!
Now please, make this
foolish fellow more like you.
That is the plan Mrs. H.
That is the plan.
So you are staying?
I will give you the
deposit tomorrow morning.
Oh that's great!
So did you like the Ashram?
Not the Ashram.
Home.
Ah!
THAILAND